<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/code/pfs.css"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The pretended country squire, with an account of his last will and testament: together with a whole dicar of legacies bequeathed to his new-found friends; who at length, to their unspeakable sorrow, are left in the lurch. : To the tune of, Merry and Glad.</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 5KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 2 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2016-02">2016-02 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B43700</idno><idno type="EEBO-CITATION">767615928</idno>
  <idno type="VID">212630</idno>
  <idno type="EEBO-PROQUEST">2240869836</idno>
  
            <idno type="OCLC"> 767615928</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocn 767615928</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing P3317</idno>
            <availability><p>This keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above is co-owned by the
    institutions providing financial support to the Early English Books Online Text Creation
    Partnership. This text is available for reuse, according to the terms of <ref target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"> Creative Commons 0 1.0 Universal
    licence</ref>. The text can be copied, modified, distributed and performed, even for commercial
    purposes, all without asking permission.</p></availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt><relatedItem type="facs" target="https://data.historicaltexts.jisc.ac.uk/view?pubId=eebo-e"/>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B43700)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 212630)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English Books, 1641-1700 ; 3023:8)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>The pretended country squire, with an account of his last will and testament: together with a whole dicar of legacies bequeathed to his new-found friends; who at length, to their unspeakable sorrow, are left in the lurch. : To the tune of, Merry and Glad.</title>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([1] p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed for P. Brooksby, J. Deacon, J. Blare, and J. Back.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London] :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1692.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Place of publication suggested by Wing (2nd ed.).</note>
                  <note>"Licensed according to order."</note>
                  <note>In two columns.</note>
                  <note>Without music.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in: The National Library of Scotland.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,363 texts created during Phase 1 of the project have been released into the public domain as of 1 January 2015. Anyone can now take and use these texts for their own purposes, but we respectfully request that due credit and attribution is given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Full documentation of the original data capture process is available from the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.
   All versions of the texts are now archived and freely available for download. See <ref target="https://textcreationpartnership.org/faq/#faq05">the TCP Download FAQ</ref>
   for detailed information. The TEI P5 versions are also freely available from the <ref target="https://github.com/textcreationpartnership">TCP Github repository</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp" matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)" replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term type="genre_form">Ballads --  England --  17th century.</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Broadsides --  England --  17th century.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014-06 </date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-10 </date>
            <label>Anne Simpson </label>Sampled and proofread </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-10 </date>
            <label>Anne Simpson</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited </change>
         <change>
            <date>2015-03 </date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion </change>
      <change><date>2021-05 </date><label>lb</label>TEI P5 conversion </change></revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:212630:1"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:212630:2"/>
            <head>THE Pretended Country Squire, WITH An Account of his Last WILL and TESTAMENT: Together with a whole Dicar of Legacies bequeathed to his New-found Friends; who at length, to their unspeakable Sorrow, are left in the Lurch.</head>
            <opener>To the Tune or, <hi>Merry and Glad.</hi>
            </opener>
            <q>
               <floatingText xml:lang="eng">
                  <body>
                     <div type="license" subtype="order_to_print">
                        <p>
                           <hi>Lice-sed according to Order.</hi>
                        </p>
                     </div>
                  </body>
               </floatingText>
            </q>
            <lg n="1">
               <head>1.</head>
               <l>COme listen, while I here unfold</l>
               <l>as strange a Prank as e're was known,</l>
               <l>Of one being Fifty-five years Old,</l>
               <l>who near <hi>Temple-Bar</hi> wander'd all alone.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="2">
               <head>2.</head>
               <l>The Grave appearance of his Face,</l>
               <l>and Cloath'd in a dejected Weed,</l>
               <l>Straight caused a <hi>Baker</hi> near that place,</l>
               <l>to ask him of what he stood in need.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="3">
               <head>3.</head>
               <l>I lack a Lodging Sir, he cry'd,</l>
               <l>as being but a Stranger here:</l>
               <l>The <hi>Baker</hi> immediately reply'd,</l>
               <l>thou art welcome to me, kind Friend, ne'r fear.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="4">
               <head>4.</head>
               <l>This kindness he could not deny,</l>
               <l>he never stood disputing long,</l>
               <l>'Twas good to embrace a Friend, for why,</l>
               <l>his Pockets was but, two Shillings strong.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="5">
               <head>5.</head>
               <l>Now while he was residing there,</l>
               <l>in hopes to live at a Splendid rate,</l>
               <l>He did to the <hi>Baker</hi> then declare,</l>
               <l>that he was a Man of a vast Estate.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="6">
               <head>6.</head>
               <l>Quoth he, I stand engag'd this day,</l>
               <l>for full five hundred pounds, or more,</l>
               <l>The which I have sworn I'll never pay,</l>
               <l>although I have thousands lies by in store.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="7">
               <head>7.</head>
               <l>'Tis for this cause I do abscond,</l>
               <l>and come to <hi>London</hi> in this sort:</l>
               <l>The <hi>Baker</hi> of such a Guest grew fond,</l>
               <l>believing his feign'd and false Report.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="8">
               <head>8.</head>
               <l>At length this Spark fell Sick and weak,</l>
               <l>and they no Costs or Charges spare,</l>
               <l>For learned Physicians with speed they seek,</l>
               <l>the better to shew their indulgent Care.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="9">
               <head>9.</head>
               <l>At their own Cost, they purchas'd free,</l>
               <l>what ever Art or Skill could name,</l>
               <l>Supposing their languishing Guest to be</l>
               <l>a Country Squire of worth and Fame.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="10">
               <head>10.</head>
               <l>The <hi>Baker</hi> in Sobs did sigh full sore,</l>
               <l>grieving for him with melting eye,</l>
               <l>And being Collector of the Poor,</l>
               <l>he brought a kind Brother to weep likewise</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="11">
               <head>11.</head>
               <l>With Sobs they did his Chamber fill,</l>
               <l>nothing but bitter sighs he hears,</l>
               <l>At which he resolv'd to make his Will,</l>
               <l>to gratifie them for all their Tears.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="12">
               <head>12.</head>
               <l>He thus begins with Christian care,</l>
               <l>and gives them all to understand,</l>
               <l>A Cousen he means to make his Heir</l>
               <l>now of his head Manour, House and Land.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="13">
               <head>13.</head>
               <l>The honest <hi>Baker</hi> next he Will'd,</l>
               <l>to have a branch of his Estate,</l>
               <l>In token of Love which he beheld,</l>
               <l>in Christian-like friendship from him of late.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="14">
               <head>14.</head>
               <l>The <hi>Bakers</hi> Wife, Son, Daughter dear,</l>
               <l>be many hundred pounds did leave,</l>
               <l>A Generous Soul he did appear,</l>
               <l>each reckond they had not much cause to <hi>grieve</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="15">
               <head>15.</head>
               <l>He left them Horses, House and Land,</l>
               <l>his tender love did so abound,</l>
               <l>So much as the Nurse, we understand,</l>
               <l>he left the sum of a hundred pound.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="16">
               <head>16.</head>
               <l>The Master would not let his Boy</l>
               <l>come near the Squire while Sick he lay,</l>
               <l>Lest he should a Legacy then enjoy,</l>
               <l>to set up a Bake-house another day.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="17">
               <head>17.</head>
               <l>His Gifts, we see, were not a few,</l>
               <l>no Man was e're more kind than he;</l>
               <l>Nay, he left them Rings and Mourning too,</l>
               <l>so Liberal was he in each degree.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="18">
               <head>18.</head>
               <l>For a Rich Coffin straight they go,</l>
               <l>his Sp<gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>endid Glory they'd not blast;</l>
               <l>Twelve pounds on the same they did bestow,</l>
               <l>but here comes the Devil of all at last.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="19">
               <head>19.</head>
               <l>This Sham-pretended Squires Love,</l>
               <l>was found e're he was laid in Grave.</l>
               <l>Since he an Impastor thus did pr<gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ve.</l>
               <l>now never a Penny they'r like to have.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="20">
               <head>20.</head>
               <l>His new Friends in a Rage did say,</l>
               <l>they never knew so vile a Cheat;</l>
               <l>Therefore his Rich Coffin they took away,</l>
               <l>and hardly alford him a Winding-Sheet.</l>
            </lg>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>Printed for <hi>P. Brocksly. J. Deacon, J. Blare,</hi> and <hi>J. Back.</hi> 1692.</p>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>